Hi there, I'm Tracy Goodwin and I'm the red sweater lady and today we're going to be talking about how to build a character.
And, this is primarily for actors, but possibly for directors or anyone involved in humorous interpretation, dramatic interpretation, any UIL events, or maybe you're just having to learn some material for an acting class or a speech class.
There are some definite things that you want to do when you develop a character, some very specific questions that you want to answer and some very specific things that you want to know about your character.
And I'm going to talk about those today and tell you exactly what you need to do to build a strong lifelike character because that's what we're really trying to do.
We do certain things in life.
We act a certain way.
We have a certain background.
We look a certain way.
We speak a certain way.
We walk a certain way.
And that's what we're doing when we're taking on a character, whether it's in a play or even for a grade in a classroom, is we want to recreate, or be, a real character, or just like a real person.
So, I want to talk to you today about all the things that you need to consider so that your character can be perceived as real and your character can be fully developed.